<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conor Gaffney</title>
    <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.conorgaffney.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Conor Gaffney's weblog and other valuable information</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 15:11:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 15:11:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>

    
    <item>
      <title>Inequality in boom and bust</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2013/03/18/inequality-in-boom-and-bust/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2013/03/18/inequality-in-boom-and-bust</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just started G.A. Cohen&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href='http://books.google.com/books?id=oeUQjOLNY-wC&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;amp;dq=self+ownership+freedom+equality&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=36xHUd6pK9Kl4AOk0YGYBg&amp;amp;ved=0CDAQ6AEwAA#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=false'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Self Ownership, Freedom, and Equality&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and the following struck me as particularly relevant given &lt;a href='http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/19/business/global/19iht-cyprus19.html'&gt;today&amp;#8217;s news about Cyprus&lt;/a&gt; and the return of the spectre of financial crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;When aggregate wealth is increasing, the condition of those at the bottom of society, and in the world, can improve, even while the distance between them and the better off does not diminish. Where such improvement occurs (and it has occured, on a substantial scale, for many disadvantaged groups), egalitarian justice does not cease to demand equality, but that demand can seem shrill, even dangerous, if the worse off are steadily growing better off, even though they are not catching up with those above them. When, however, progress must give way to regress, when average material living standards must fall, then poor people and poor nations can no longer hope to approach the levels of amenity which are now enjoyed by the world's well off. Sharply falling average standards mean that settling for limitless improvement, instead of equality, ceases to be an option, and huge disparities of wealth become correspondingly more intolerable, from a moral point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cohen&amp;#8217;s thought deserves a more serious consideration than I&amp;#8217;m in a position to give, but at first blush it strikes me as a serious challenge to &lt;a href='http://plato.stanford.edu/entries/justice-distributive/#Difference'&gt;Rawls&amp;#8217; difference principle.&lt;/a&gt; The difference principle countenances economic inequalities so long as the unequal situation benefits the least advantaged in society. However, insofar as systematic inequality &lt;em&gt;causes&lt;/em&gt; moments of general economic regress (which we recognize as the &amp;#8220;bust&amp;#8221; of business cycles or periodic crisis moments in capitalism) thereby resulting in a situation in which inequalities do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; benefit the bottom of society, then the &amp;#8220;basic structure&amp;#8221; is one which does not result in an acceptable &amp;#8220;pure procedural justice&amp;#8221; (to use two of Rawls&amp;#8217; terms) and must be revised.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is TNTP a scam?</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2013/03/12/is-tntp-a-scam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2013/03/12/is-tntp-a-scam</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- get TNTP budget. how much on teacher recruitment, training, etc. and how much on policy/advocacy things? --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Racism is more than just bigotry</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2013/03/08/racism-is-more-than-just-bigotry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2013/03/08/racism-is-more-than-just-bigotry</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two days ago, the New York Times published an op-ed by Ta-Nehisi Coates called &lt;a href='http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/07/opinion/coates-the-good-racist-people.html'&gt;&amp;#8220;The Good, Racist People&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;. In it, Coates takes up the recent harassment of actor Forest Whitaker at a deli in Morningside Heights as an illustration of the almost invisible form that racism has taken in 21st century America. While waiting in line, Whitaker was approached by an employee of the deli, accused of shoplifting, and then frisked. The Oscar-winning actor had of course not shoplifted from the store (but someone else had), and upon realizing this the mortified employee quickly apologized for his &amp;#8220;sincere mistake.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coates notes that the employee probably did make a &lt;em&gt;sincere&lt;/em&gt; mistake and is most likely a &amp;#8220;decent man,&amp;#8221; as the deli owner and other people who know him have claimed. He probably did genuinely think Whitaker was a thief. Indeed, we have no reason to suspect that the employee harbors any sort of active discrimination towards people of color. At the very most, we can fault the transgressor with having internalized some sort of subconscious discriminatory suspicion and fear of black people. This is no trivial point. A country in which every black person is a suspect, even those we see on TV and in movies every day, is a country that is existentially hostile to a significant portion of its population.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I don&amp;#8217;t think this is the only point that Coates is making. He is also concerned with exploring the contradiction of being both this kind of unwitting racist and also a &amp;#8220;decent man.&amp;#8221; After all, Coates admits, the deli employee is both. And he wonders out loud, going through a list of similar micro-aggressions (a black president required to prove he was really born in America, whites keeping blacks out of their neighborhoods and claiming in total sincerity that they are not racist), why this contradiction is at all tolerable in our nominally anti-racist society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I can venture one guess as to why this contradiction is not just tolerable, but so unremarkable that we discuss it only when a victim of hidden racism publishes an eloquent op-ed in the NYT: we don&amp;#8217;t have a robust concept of equality in our current political conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may seem odd to claim that Americans aren&amp;#8217;t really concerned with equality in the days when the LGBTQ rights movement is at the peak of a shockingly rapid ascent and &lt;a href='http://www.americanprogress.org/issues/economy/news/2012/03/05/11193/americans-care-about-economic-inequality'&gt;a majority of Americans think economic inequality is the greatest obstacle to social mobility.&lt;/a&gt; But I mean that we don&amp;#8217;t have a &lt;em&gt;robust&lt;/em&gt; concept of equality. Although a majority of Americans may be concerned about economic inequality and favor equality of rights for minorities, there is little discussion that connects economic inequalities with individual instances of prejudice. So long as these two forms of inequality &amp;#8211; one structural, the other personal &amp;#8211; are seen as separate and unrelated, we won&amp;#8217;t have a coherent idea of social inequality that can be used in the service of political action. So long as we understand the Whitaker affair as a case of a decent man making a sincere mistake, we have no problem to attack, no cause to address to ensure that decent men no longer make these kind of deeply damaging mistakes. Mistakes which Coates is right to point out effectively tell black children &amp;#8220;We were never meant to be part of the American story&amp;#8230;Don&amp;#8217;t leave home. They don&amp;#8217;t want you around.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walter Benn Michaels has &lt;a href='http://www.lrb.co.uk/v31/n16/walter-benn-michaels/what-matters'&gt;an excellent article in the LRB&lt;/a&gt; that explores how neoliberalism has effectively transformed the discussion of inequality in a discussion of prejudice, thus deflating any political animus to address the root causes of social and political differences that occur along race, gender, and class lines. I believe when Benn Michaels examines how the US could become more anti-racist and anti-sexist in the past 40 years, while at the same time become massively more unequal along racial and gender lines, he is analyzing the phenomenon that Coates feels in the instance of the Forest Whitaker&amp;#8217;s insult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Benn Michaels:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;That is, once you start redefining the problem of class difference as the problem of class prejudice – once you complete the transformation of race, gender and class into racism, sexism and classism – you no longer have to worry about the redistribution of wealth. You can just fight over whether poor people should be treated with contempt or respect. And while, in human terms, respect seems the right way to go, politically it's just as empty as contempt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And from Coates:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;The other day I walked past this particular deli. I believe its owners to be good people. I felt ashamed at withholding business for something far beyond the merchant's reach. I mentioned this to my wife. My wife is not like me. When she was 6, a little white boy called her cousin a nigger, and it has been war ever since. “What if they did that to your son?” she asked.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;And right then I knew that I was tired of good people, that I had had all the good people I could take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belle Gulch</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2013/02/09/belle-gulch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2013/02/09/belle-gulch</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href='http://www.nytimes.com/2013/02/08/opinion/detroit-sinks-with-belle-isle.html'&gt;&amp;#8220;Detroit, the Billionaires Playground,&amp;#8221; &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, Feb 7, 2013&lt;/a&gt;, a (short) story of economic recovery, economic inequality, and libertarian dreams riding high atop big-government bailouts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Belle_Isle_Park'&gt;Belle Isle&lt;/a&gt; is an iconic island park managed by the City of Detroit. Designed in the late 1880s by Frederick Law Olmsted &amp;#8211; the man who brought you Central Park and the World&amp;#8217;s Fair &amp;#8211; the beloved public space is now too expensive for the city to keep up, and consequently at risk of sinking forever into the Detroit River.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But fear not, a group of civic-minded business barons have offered to generously save Belle Isle:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Belle Isle was recently at the center of a different moneymaking scheme. A group of wealthy libertarians suggested that private investors buy the island from the city for the nice, round, Dr. Evil-ish sum of $1 billion and transform it into an independent, self-governing territory. With the price for citizenship set at $300,000, the Commonwealth of Belle Isle would exist as a sort of free-market paradise; within 30 years, the group’s Web site predicted, the island would be known as the &quot; 'Midwest Tiger,' rivaling Singapore as an economic miracle.&quot; One can order from that Web site a novella about this future Belle Isle, which describes the commonwealth’s low taxes, minimal government, even its own currency (called — seriously — &quot;the Rand&quot;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(one reason) Why the history of Bosnia is important</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2013/01/31/importance-of-history-bosnia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2013/01/31/importance-of-history-bosnia</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just finished reading Noel Malcolm&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href='http://books.google.com/books/about/Bosnia.html?id=Cvk6oMf9R7AC'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bosnia: A Short History&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Malcolm, in addition to being one of the foremost intellectual historians in the world and an authority on Thomas Hobbes, also does history of the Balkans and moonlights as an magazine editor and a syndicated columnist. Sheesh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s an excellent and extremely readable brief history, covering events from 1180 to 1995 (the book was published in 1994 and again in 1996). It has an especially fascinating and even-handed discussion of the mysterious medieval Bosnian church, an institution whose schismatic and folk-pagan dimensions have been often exaggerated and enlisted in the service of nationalist mythologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But perhaps the most valuable element of Malcolm&amp;#8217;s short book is the contribution he claims its dispassionate brand of historical inquiry can make towards clarifying and calming modern political hysterias. Malcolm wrote the book largely during the genocidal conflict that destroyed the nation of Bosnia. He introduces his historical work with a damning critique of the ahistorical arguments that not only framed the inflammatory rhetoric of Yugoslav nationalist politicians, but more importantly were bandied about in the West to excuse its shameful inaction in the face of atrocity and genocide. Passing off systematic state-sponsored violence as the simple playing-out of &amp;#8220;ancient ethnic hatreds&amp;#8221; was a common refrain among British and American statesmen and journalists in the 1990s and still is today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an excerpt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;The years 1992 and 1993 will be remembered as the years in which a European country was destoryed...&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Pardoxically, the most important reason for studying Bosnia's history is that it enables one to see that the history of Bosnia in itself does not explain the origins of this war...The biggest obstacle to all understanding of the conflict is the assumption that what has happened in that country is the product -- natural, spontaneous and at the same time necessary -- of forces lying within Bosnia's own internal history. That is the myth which was carefully propogated by those who caused the conflict, who wanted the world to believe that what they and their gunmen were doing was not done by them, but by impersonal and inevitable historical forces beyond anyone's control.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Of course it is easy to go through the history of a country such as Bosnia picking out instances of regional divisions, violence and ungovernability...Commentators who like to give some hastily-assembled historical authority to their writings can always pick out a few bloody episodes from the past and say: 'It was ever thus.' One could perform the same exercise with, for instance, France, picking out the religious wars of the sixteenth century, the barbarity of the St Bartholomew's Day massacre [etc.]...But if a number of foreign-backed politicians and military commanders began bombarding Paris with heavy artillery tomorrow, we would not sit back and say that it was just an inevitable consequence of 'ancient French hatreds'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redesigning this site</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2012/11/30/redesigning-this-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2012/11/30/redesigning-this-site</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My website was in sore need of an overhaul. I hadn&amp;#8217;t really looked at it seriously in more than a year, and I won&amp;#8217;t go into all the embarassing problems. But suffice it to list: the site was not responsive (still on the 960px grid system of yore), it had an unmanageably long front page displaying every post, I hadn&amp;#8217;t fixed a broken implementation of Twitter&amp;#8217;s API, and the site, overall, was set up like any out-of-the-box blog + static pages concoction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Ew' src='/img/posts/old-site-homepage.png' /&gt; &lt;small class='caption'&gt;This is what it looked like&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Double ew' src='/img/posts/old-site-unresponsive.png' /&gt; &lt;small class='caption'&gt;This is what it looked like on a smaller screen&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Triple ew' src='/img/posts/old-site-resume.png' /&gt; &lt;small class='caption'&gt;And this is what my resume page, on the same site, looked like. Completely different!&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I wanted to learn about my site&amp;#8217;s few visitors. A glance at my analytics dashboard revealed that the vast majority of visitors were new, and most spent a few seconds on the home (blog) page before going to /about or /resume. So I could pretty safely conclude what I suspected all along: that most people who came to my site were looking for more information about me and not coming regularly to read my fascinating, and very occasional, blog posts. Clearly, my resume and other professional information needed to be front and center. But more than this, the content of my website should all be roughly focused around things I&amp;#8217;ve done for work or for school. My blog really does not have a following (sorry, mom).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I only had one real idea when it came to re-designing my site: my content is and will be mostly text, not images, so typography would be important. There was a problem: I know nothing about type. So I decided to just pick one that I liked and take it from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/adobe/Source-Sans-Pro'&gt;Adobe&amp;#8217;s Source Sans Pro&lt;/a&gt; is a pretty simple sans-serif font that also has some nice character spacing, so it works well both in short labels (i.e. on buttons or nav links) and longer blocks of text. This made figuring out the typography for my site &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; simpler. I could use one font to do it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having found the central element of my re-design, I now was ready to start laying things out. After two months with the frontend team at OFA, I had a healthy fear-of-god kind of appreciation for responsive, mobile-first design. But I was still in the clutch of old habits and had difficulty conceptualizing a design that was fluid across screen sizes. At best I could think of three different views: mobile, tablet, and desktop. But that is an onerous way to think of making a website. It&amp;#8217;s actually thinking of making three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I stepped back. At this point the only thing my website had was its &lt;strong&gt;content&lt;/strong&gt;. That is, all I wanted it to do was present information, all of which could be presented in text or images. So I decided to put all of my &amp;#8220;content&amp;#8221; into an HTML document to see what I had, how it actually looked in a browser, and decide how it should look. In other words, I would give &lt;a href='http://www.alistapart.com/articles/responsive-comping-obtaining-signoff-with-mockups/'&gt;designing in-browser&lt;/a&gt; a shot. Well the going was slow. I stared at a prototype of a layout for about a week, not really understanding what was wrong with it or what needed to be changed. I even opened Photoshop in a few moments of desperation thinking that making some mockups would help me move forward. Thankfully, I was too lazy to make any real headway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually I had a breakthrough. I removed the grid that I had initially put my content into in the prototype and just looked at how the unstyled page flowed. It suddenly made a lot more sense. Naturally, I had written my &amp;#8220;content&amp;#8221; in the order it was meant to be presented. What I wanted the reader to see first I put first, and followed that also, in the logic of the presentation, followed that. So messing up this sequence with sidebars and other stuff just wasn&amp;#8217;t a good idea. Then it became incredibly simple to find colors and accent links and buttons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the two small lessons I learned this time around: &lt;strong&gt;design in broswer&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;design around content&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I've been doing lately</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2012/09/27/what-ive-been-doing-lately/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2012/09/27/what-ive-been-doing-lately</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just in case anyone was wondering, I recently moved to Chicago to help &lt;a href='http://www.barackobama.com'&gt;re-elect President Obama.&lt;/a&gt; There will be a bunch of updates after November. &lt;pre style='line-height:1.1em; margin-left:140px'&gt;&lt;code style='background-color:#FFF; color:#96BE5E'&gt;
              .:+uuuuuuuuuuu+:.
          ./sssssssssssssssssssss/-
       ./aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa/.
     .+uuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuu+.
   `/sssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssss/
  `aaaaaaaaaaaaa:-`       `-:aaaaaaaaaaaaa.
 `uuuuuuuuuuu/.               ./uuuuuuuuuuu.
 sssssssssss.                   .sssssssssss`
-aaaaaaaaaa`                     `+aaaaaaaaa:
uuuuuuuuuu.                       `uuuuuuuuuu
ssssss-```                         ```-ssssss
`       ....aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa....       `
...+uuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuu+...
-ssssssssssssss+//-```                  `````
 aaaaa+/:-`            ...aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa.
 `/-``        ..::uuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuu.
        .:/+sssssssssssssssss-```      ````
     /aaaaaaaaaaaaa+/:-``       ...aaaaaa
     .+uuuuuuu/:-``        .-:/+uuuuuuu-
       ./s/-`         -:+sssssssssss+.
                  -/aaaaaaaaaaaaa+-`
              .:+usausausausa+:-
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An interview with Simon Dinnerstein</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2012/08/30/interview-with-simon-dinnerstein/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2012/08/30/interview-with-simon-dinnerstein</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My dear friend &lt;a href='http://kaitlinpomerantz.weebly.com/'&gt;Katie&lt;/a&gt; interviewed artist Simon Dinnerstein recently. &lt;a href='http://bombsite.com/issues/1000/articles/6754'&gt;They talked about Dinnerstein&amp;#8217;s monumental &amp;#8220;Fulbright Triptych&amp;#8221; (1971-4, see below), the purpose and process of making a piece of art, the figurative tradition, and conventions and criticism.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Dinnersteins the Fulbright Triptych' src='http://bombsite.com/images/attachments/0015/0722/TRYPTYCH_body.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is really an affirming conversation. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SD&lt;/strong&gt; ...Someone mentioned recently that this painting is sort of like “a geography of the unconscious,” and I really like that expression. But the thing also about this is that it doesn’t have a strategy. In other words, it’s something that just kind of happened. And I think that art that has a strategy, you will know that it has a strategy, and it depletes the art.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KP&lt;/strong&gt; Can you talk more about that? Are you talking about a gimmick?&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SD&lt;/strong&gt; Well, I mean work that has a cunning about it, a canniness—work that was figured out before it was begun. I think that undercuts the art. Really important art—whether it’s literature, or dance, or music, or painting, or drawing—it really happens. It doesn’t have a strategy, and I think sometimes you can tell if the art is natural or if it has a kind of agenda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://bombsite.com/issues/1000/articles/6754'&gt;Read the whole thing.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greece in 2012</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2012/07/18/greece-in-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2012/07/18/greece-in-2012</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Did I ever tell you about that time I went to Greece with my younger brother and some friends from college?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Zooming along in a water taxi from Hydra' src='/img/posts/hydra.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started the morning of June 6, when our dissertations were due. As previously arranged, I met two friends in the graduate research room (GRR), an elevated, 24-hour box of computers in the history faculty with free printing and all varieties of desperation. The atmosphere was faintly buzzing. I saw some coursemates who had not had to fortune to leave the GRR the night before, one smiling from behind empty bags of gummy bears and a stack of the classics of Western political thought from Montesquieu to Cohen. We printed our dissertations and walked to the graduate union to get them bound. It looked like it was going to rain. It didn&amp;#8217;t rain. Then it rained a little. We waited in the cafe at the union while our dissertations were bound. We had received an alarming email from the administration weeks earlier reminding us that June 6 was the Queen&amp;#8217;s jubilee and it was unclear how this would impact the paper binding in Cambridge. It was over quickly, and was inexpensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It didn&amp;#8217;t rain as we walked back to the history faculty and handed our papers in. &amp;#8220;Um, well done!&amp;#8221; our course secretary told us. It was done. So I went home and stacked books to be returned to the library and put all the documents on my desktop into a folder called &amp;#8220;MPhil.&amp;#8221; Then I cut across the cemetery to a pub to meet some friends. The nervous feeling of anti-climax wore off soon after the first drink and slow waves of relief began to roll in. It was nice to sit and talk to L&amp;#8211; and A&amp;#8211; about our feelings of frustration with the (perhaps unnecessarily) rushed process of writing a 20k word dissertation in one month. Is this what an academic career is going to be like? Surely not. It cannot be. We debated. And then, in a pathetic fallacy, it began to pour and there was thunder which is unusual anywhere in Britain. As the storm ended we realized we were quite drunk, quite exhausted, and nervous with something which I told myself was nervousness at having a lot of things to do now, but not knowing where or when to begin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Trinity St' src='/img/posts/anne_cam.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Anne Mishkind took the above photo. It&amp;#8217;s nice! It&amp;#8217;s also Trinity St, Cambridge)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did have a lot of things to do. I had to return my library books. I had to meet my younger brother the next morning in King&amp;#8217;s Cross, and the next day we were to fly to Athens to meet two friends of mine from college and begin a two week long vacation. I had to find us a place to stay for these two weeks. And I had to relax! I had to take it easy. I just finished a very grueling master&amp;#8217;s program. With all that in mind I anxiously went searching for my coursemates, the rest of them, at a pub across town. They were in the garden of the Granta, most of them, sitting in some shape inspired by a circle, vibrating at a high frequency. We drank some more and as we left the Granta around 7 pm for the Maypole, I peeled off to go home for a rest intending to join the group in a few hours for all-night carousing, but awoke only early the next morning on top of my bed, fully clothed with my shoes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our way to Athens, Nat and I spent a dreadful six hours laid over in the Geneva airport, where Nat&amp;#8217;s bag decided to remain for the next two days. By some great stroke of luck, I found an extraordinary apartment in Athens for a great rate on AirBnb, and Heather, who had arrived many hours before me and Nat, was there to greet us when we arrived at 1:30 am. We were staying in a woman named Gina&amp;#8217;s apartment, in the neighborhood of Exarhia (ΕΞΑΡΧΙΑ), on a street that ran from Strefi Hill to Likavitos Hill. Exarhia, we were told, is &amp;#8220;where every revolution in Greek history has ever begun.&amp;#8221; It governed itself, and when the police tried to come in the neighborhood to regulate protests and public gatherings, they were simply pushed out by the residents. We were in the right neighborhood at the right time, it appeared. All thirty-two factions of the Left seemed to have a presence in Exarhia. There were posters and graffiti everywhere, my favorite of which simply said &amp;#8220;weg.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Me and Nat in Ginas apartment' src='/img/posts/heath_gina.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Me and Nat in Gina&amp;#8217;s apartment in Exarhia. Heather took this photo.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='The view from Ginas balcony' src='/img/posts/gina_apt_1.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The view from Gina&amp;#8217;s back balcony.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='The view from Lykavitos Hill' src='/img/posts/lyka_view.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There&amp;#8217;s Gina&amp;#8217;s apartment down there! From Lykavitos Hill.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent a few days in Athens. Danielle and her friend from Beirut, Emma, met us and after some furious internet searching and creative negotiating, we found an apartment to stay in on the island of Poros and a way to get there. The apartment was owned by a young IT professional named Agamemnon who was also running for parliament as the leader of his own, newly founded party. He didn&amp;#8217;t seem to want to go into details about his party&amp;#8217;s platform, but after calling Syriza crazy he said we Americans would call his party a center-left party. I&amp;#8217;m not sure if Agamemnon appreciated that center-left in America is pretty far-right everywhere else in the world. Maybe he did. He was good at negotiations. The resting state of the entire trip was one of mild logistical nightmare, and of course the leg in Agamemnon&amp;#8217;s island getaway provided no exception. Agamemnon, the keys to his place in Poros, and our merry band of travelers were all in Athens. However, the last ferry from Athens to Poros left at 6 pm, before Agamemnon could get out of work and deliver us his keys. We offered to stop by his work &amp;#8211; out of the question. He offered to get his mother to drop them off to us in Exarhia &amp;#8211; quickly eliminated. He finally suggested that our group split into two, half taking the last ferry from Athens, and half going with him to Poros by car and a later ferry from the Peloponnese. It worked. In extreme vacation &lt;em&gt;geist&lt;/em&gt;, Heather, Nat, and I waited on the quayside in Poros town sipping white wine and watching the sun set while Danielle, and Emma were hurtling towards us across the Peloponnese in Agamemnon&amp;#8217;s car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Poros' src='/img/posts/nat_poros.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A photo Nat took while we were waiting in Poros town.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We picked Poros at random from Athens, but ended up lucking out. The island is mostly frequented by Greeks and is largely passed over in Lonely Planets and other guidebooks which shunt the worst of the globetrotting late-capitalist imperialists to other islands like Santorini and Mykonos. It was suitably quiet for our group and Agamemnon&amp;#8217;s apartment was close to two very nice beaches: Love Bay and Russian Bay. The night before I left the UK for Greece, a friend who had been several times told me that the climate and landscape in Greece are the most remarkable aspects of the country, and the landscape feels hospitable in an elemental way that gives all those dangerously essential claims about the birthplace of Western civilization some new dimension that must be contended with. It is a romantic place, and not just because there are beaches named Love Bay. Giorgos Seferis knows what I mean:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.poetryfoundation.org/poem/181958' target='_blank'&gt;Mythistorema 7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Westward the sea merges with a mountain range.&lt;br /&gt;
	From our left the south wind blows and drives us mad,&lt;br /&gt;
	the kind of wind that strips bones of their flesh.&lt;br /&gt;
	Our house among pines and carobs.&lt;br /&gt;
	Large windows. Large tables&lt;br /&gt;
	for writing you the letters we’ve been writing&lt;br /&gt;
	so many months now, dropping them&lt;br /&gt;
	into the space between us in order to fill it up.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Star of dawn, when you lowered your eyes&lt;br /&gt;
	our hours were sweeter than oil&lt;br /&gt;
	on a wound, more joyful than cold water&lt;br /&gt;
	to the palate, more peaceful than a swan’s wings.&lt;br /&gt;
	You held our life in the palm of your hand.&lt;br /&gt;
	After the bitter bread of exile,&lt;br /&gt;
	at night if we remain in front of the white wall&lt;br /&gt;
	your voice approaches us like the hope of fire;&lt;br /&gt;
	and again this wind hones&lt;br /&gt;
	a razor against our nerves.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Each of us writes you the same thing&lt;br /&gt;
	and each falls silent in the other’s presence,&lt;br /&gt;
	watching, each of us, the same world separately&lt;br /&gt;
	the light and darkness on the mountain range&lt;br /&gt;
	and you.&lt;br /&gt;
	Who will lift this sorrow from our hearts?&lt;br /&gt;
	Yesterday evening a heavy rain and again today&lt;br /&gt;
	the covered sky burdens us. Our thoughts –&lt;br /&gt;
	like the pine needles of yesterday’s downpour&lt;br /&gt;
	bunched up and useless in front of our doorway —&lt;br /&gt;
	would build a collapsing tower.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Among these decimated villages&lt;br /&gt;
	on this promontory, open to the south wind&lt;br /&gt;
	with the mountain range in front of us hiding you,&lt;br /&gt;
	who will appraise for us the sentence to oblivion?&lt;br /&gt;
	Who will accept our offering, at this close of autumn?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='The other side of Poros' src='/img/posts/v_bay.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Nat in Russian Bay' src='/img/posts/nat_r_bay.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent four days on Poros. On one day, we took a ferry to Hydra. Hydra was rich during the 18th and 19th centuries. It had some fancy shipbuilders, a few admirals, and other big shots in the Ottoman navy. The island has a lot of beautiful old mansions, no cars, and not a few donkeys. By donkeys I mean the equine and the type of American tourist who thinks it&amp;#8217;s neat or something to busk around Europe. We hightailed it out of Hydra town to a nearby beach once the crusty buskers discovered each other and began busking back and forth in some facile display of liberated spirits. Despite Hydra&amp;#8217;s beautiful streetscapes and total lack of cars, there was a bit too much English spoken for our taste (and spoken on too limited a range of subjects: &amp;#8220;I got so wasted last night,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Before you say anything, let me remind you I am wasted,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Do you want to get wasted now?&amp;#8221;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Dr. Gold in Hydra' src='/img/posts/heath_hydra.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dr. Gold in Hydra, sans repulsive tourists.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, as recompense for our quiet cultural suffering on Hydra, we returned to Poros to see our good friend Dan pulling into port on a ferry from Athens. He had just arrived from New York and was beginning his own tour of the Balkans and central Europe by joining us in Greece. Dan had somehow been convinced that there were &amp;#8220;no more seats in coach&amp;#8221; on his ferry and he would have to spring the extra €9 for &amp;#8220;business class,&amp;#8221; and as the sun set behind the Hellenic Seaways Flying Cat 1, there was Dan waving from the business class deck, the only passenger in business class sporting a beard and an internal frame backpack. We would only spend one more night and day on Poros before returning to Athens. But the next day, our last day, contained one of the more successful minor adventures of the trip. We woke up relatively early to spend the day at Russian Bay before our evening ferry departed. As we were walking along the road from our house we noticed several extraordinarily large yachts anchored close in to shore. One, sporting a British flag, looked to be the size of a medium warship. In Russian Bay, there was a smaller, but still quite enormous yacht (probably 130 feet), flying an American flag. Dan and I were swimming past it on our way to explore a small island in the middle of Russian Bay and Dan suggested we try to say hello and see if they&amp;#8217;d be interested in having us on board. After all we were on vacation and so, very evidently, were these guys. Who doesn&amp;#8217;t like to meet people and have a little adventure on vacation? Dan and I called out in our friendliest voices and from about 50 feet above us a head appeared over the deck railing, glanced at the two sunburnt men smiling in the water, and returned back to whatever Xanadu it had momentarily been distracted from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had been rejected, unsurprisingly, and slowly swam out to the island as originally planned swallowing the bitter conventional wisdom of exclusion that would not even be suspended here on this really exceptional vacation. Of course we would not be welcomed onto a stranger&amp;#8217;s massive luxury yacht. But having the obvious confirmed can be depressing. But it can also be comic. As Dan and I were swimming back to the beach from our island, on which we regained equilibrium with a thrilling sun salutation, we heard the unmistakable voice of Heather Gold from somewhere in the vicinity of the unfriendly yacht:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Hey are you guys American?&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Something unintelligible from the yacht.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Danielle, Heather, and Emma were swimming up to the side of the yacht, as Dan and I had half an hour earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Yeah! We&amp;#8217;re from New York! Yeah, New York!&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Again, something unintelligible from the yacht.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Watch this,&amp;#8221; Dan said to me, &amp;#8220;They&amp;#8217;re going to get on the yacht.&amp;#8221; They got on the yacht. Of course three cute girls would be welcomed onto whatever boat in Greece they chose to swim up alongside. The bigger the boat, the more likely they are to get on, probably. So Dan and I laughed at the scene and then sat there treading water, unsure about what to do. We still wanted to go on the yacht. Now that the girls were on board, could we just swim up and ask to join our friends? Or would that be unwelcome and get them kicked off? We debated as we watched the girls take what looked like glasses of champagne from their hosts on the top deck. Dan pointed out that in a just and efficient universe our friends would mention to their hosts that two of their friends were out in the bay treading water, and would it be ok if they came up? That seems so sensible, I agreed with Dan, that it has to happen. So we waited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It became clear after a while that Dan and I would have to invite ourselves on board, and so we swam up to the massive yacht, again, but this time explained that our friends were on board. We were promptly invited on, given towels, and led up to the top deck to join Heather, Emma, and Danielle and a group of about five other women and one man, who were clearly the ones in charge of the yacht. We joined the group at the table, were offered some wine, and introduced ourselves. The conversation went pleasantly, with curious silences every now and then. The man introduced himself as Tom. His voice sounded very familiar. Two of the women wore big sunglasses, chain smoked, and didn&amp;#8217;t say anything. The others told us they were from the states, the South originally, though they lived in LA and New York now for work. At one point, Danielle, picking up on some earlier thread of the conversation that Dan and I had been treading water during, asked &amp;#8220;Tom, how long has your radio show been on?&amp;#8221; At this moment, I realized I was on &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tom_Joyner'&gt;Tom Joyner&amp;#8217;s&lt;/a&gt; yacht.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We couldn&amp;#8217;t stay long on Tom Joyner&amp;#8217;s yacht. They had to sail to Athens, and we had to catch the ferry to Athens. Before we jumped off to swim back in to shore, Tom invited us to meet him at a club in Athens that night at midnight. His assistant would email us the details. How exciting, we thought! That was the last time we heard from Tom Joyner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Tom Joyners yacht in Russian Bay' src='/img/posts/joyner_yacht.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tom Joyner&amp;#8217;s yacht in Russian Bay.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in Athens, we stayed again in Gina&amp;#8217;s fabulous apartment in Exarhia. We had planned to be in the city for a few days on either side of the election, in the hopes that we would witness some major democratic event. The newspapers told us stakes were high, after all. The fate of the European Union hung on this election. Syriza, the coalition of the radical left, was polling extremely favorably. They had already forced the center-right New Democracy party to a run-off in the May elections. And of course, everyone was wondering about the minor surge in support for the far-right Neo-Nazi party, the Golden Dawn. Constant news coverage of the exploits of the Golden Dawn party served only to heighten the atmosphere of extremity and tension. Golden Dawn MPs had been arrested for joining gangs roaming the streets of Athens and beating up south Asian immigrants. One Golden Dawn supporter had stabbed a communist party volunteer to death outside a voter information booth. And of course, there was &lt;a href='http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2012/jun/07/golden-dawn-tv-assault-greece'&gt;the incendiary incident of Ilias Kasidiaris, a high profile Golden Dawn MP, attacking two female members of parliament from the left on a Greek morning show&lt;/a&gt; (a 24-hour arrest warrant was issued for Kasidiaris, who had fled the studio, which he easily avoided).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Athens there were a lot of physical signs of an impending major election. Various parties staffed information tents near the university and in other high traffic areas. Almost every surface in Exarhia was plastered over with posters or political graffiti. And Greeks we met and chatted with would instantly begin discussing the election. However, the city&amp;#8217;s political temperature was no straightforward to measure. There was a significant element of resignation in the analyses we heard from people around Exarhia. Gina had told me that she didn&amp;#8217;t really think anything would change with this election, even if Syriza would win. The Euro is over, most people seemed to think, and it doesn&amp;#8217;t make a difference whether it&amp;#8217;s over for us now or several months or a year from now. The government in Athens had been so corrupt and inefficient for so long, and the European Union was irrevocably imperialist at its core, that measures to salvage anything from that unholy mess seemed foolish and not worth the effort. On the other hand, people reiterated the feeling that this was a moment of crisis and that something had to be done. The Greeks we talked to were entirely realistic about the fact that their government was broke and could conceivably stop working any day now. Agamemnon (whose judgments seemed a bit extreme) told us he had contingency plans to flee the country if, or when, the government and economy collapse. Other people were not so apocalyptic, but still expressed immediately a feeling of urgency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so on election day we waited in Exarhia to see what would happen. It was a quiet, sunny, windy day. Everything was closed as the Greeks went to the polls, and then presumably went home. In the late afternoon, as the polls were closing, Dan and I went out to walk up Lykavitos Hill and to find some groceries for dinner that night. All of the stores were shut and the streets were empty of people and cars. Pairs of police in riot gear lounged on the corners near the border of Exarhia and the more upscale neighborhoods to the north. After walking through a deserted city populated only by the occasional heavily-armored police man, Dan and I came to a surreal sight at the top of Lykavitos Hill. A polished cafe with on a marble deck overlooking the city was bustling with tourists and Greek families. Some cheesy music came from tinny speakers in the rocks around the hilltop. Next to the cafe was a tiny church from the 19th century. Two Greek soldiers were taking down the flag for the day. People were crowding onto the deck around the church to watch the sun set over Athens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Dan on Lykavitos Hill' src='/img/posts/dan_lyka.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dan and the church on Lykavitos Hill.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We walked back down into Exarhia and ran into Danielle on the street, out for a stroll. The exit polling numbers were beginning to come in, but it would be a while before anyone had a clear idea of how Greece voted. We went out in search of an open cafe or market for dinner. Most everything was closed. We were walking down a quiet pedestrian street, past a long low wall that was containing some sort of music. Dan stopped and remarked that the music sounded an awful lot like the opening of Hitchcock&amp;#8217;s &lt;em&gt;The Lady Vanishes&lt;/em&gt;. We looked at the wall for a minute. There was an opening in it covered by a thick velvet curtain and shortly a man came out and asked us if we would like to see the cinema. Inside was a large courtyard filled with gravel and a screen playing &lt;em&gt;The Man Who Knew Too Much&lt;/em&gt;. Dan was close. A few people were sitting in plastic chairs watching the film and drinking wine. Next door was an open air cafe, also largely empty. We had found dinner and a movie. We walked excitedly back through the empty streets to retrieve the rest of our group from Gina&amp;#8217;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point as we were getting ready for dinner, someone looked online for election updates and announced that the New Democracy party had won by a slim margin. That was it. The election was over and nothing had happened. Exarhia was still quiet as it had been all day. So we spent election night watching Hitchcock in a vine-covered outdoor cinema. I nodded off during the movie at some point, and after it was over we walked the few blocks back to Gina&amp;#8217;s apartment and fell asleep. Thus ended our adventures in political crises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='The outdoor cinema in Athens' src='/img/posts/athens_cinema.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cross-category equivocation</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2012/05/28/cross-category-equivocation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2012/05/28/cross-category-equivocation</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href='http://philosophy.uchicago.edu/faculty/conant.html'&gt;James Conant&amp;#8217;s&lt;/a&gt; essay on types of philosophical nonsense in Wittgenstein&amp;#8217;s &lt;em&gt;Tractatus&lt;/em&gt; and Rudolf Carnap&amp;#8217;s writing, he lists several newspaper headlines as examples of &amp;#8220;cross-category equivocation,&amp;#8221; or examples of sentences whose words have multiple meanings and aren&amp;#8217;t clear about which meaning they mean. Forget the philosophical relevance of these, I just think they&amp;#8217;re funny to read:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;British Left Waffles on Falkland Islands&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;British Push Bottles Up German Rear&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Potential Witness to Murder Drunk&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Legal Aid Advocates Worry&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Crowds Rushing To See Pope Trample 6 to Death&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Beating Witness Provides Names&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Nixon Stands Pat on Watergate Tapes&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;University Studies Mushroom&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Carter Plans Swell Deficit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s good to see that philosophers are keeping track of things like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(from &amp;#8220;Die Überwindung der Metaphysik,&amp;#8221; in &lt;em&gt;Wittgenstein in America&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Timothy McCarthy and Sean Stidd)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feelings about my dissertation</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2012/05/15/dissertation-feelings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2012/05/15/dissertation-feelings</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The cow is over there,&quot; said Ansell, lighting a match and holding it out over the carpet. No one spoke. He waited till the end of the match fell off. Then he spoke again, &quot;She is there, the cow. There, now.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;You have not proved it,&quot; said a voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I have proved it to myself.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I have proved to myself that she isn't,&quot; said the voice. &quot;The cow is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; there.&quot; Ansell frowned and lit another match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;She's there for me,&quot; he declared. &quot;I don't care whether she's there for you or not. Whether I'm in Cambridge or Iceland or dead, the cow will be there.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; E.M. Forster, &lt;em&gt;The Longest Journey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From the NYC Municipal Archives</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2012/04/28/from-the-nyc-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2012/04/28/from-the-nyc-archives</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Atlantic&amp;#8217;s &lt;em&gt;In Focus&lt;/em&gt; recently published &lt;a href='http://www.theatlantic.com/infocus/2012/04/historic-photos-from-the-nyc-municipal-archives/100286/'&gt;this selection of historic photographs from the New York City municipal archives.&lt;/a&gt; There are some really amazing pictures from the city&amp;#8217;s pre-war expansion. Interestingly, most of the selection focuses on bridges. The composition of these photos really captures the enormity of these constructions. Take these photos of the Queensboro Bridge:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Queensboro Bridge' src='http://cdn.theatlantic.com/static/infocus/nycm042712/s_n17_bpsi2117.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='The Queensboro Bridge from Long Island' src='http://cdn.theatlantic.com/static/infocus/nycm042712/s_n52_bpsi1090.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the Manhattan Bridge, gettin&amp;#8217; it&amp;#8217;s dangle on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Gettin its dangle on' src='http://cdn.theatlantic.com/static/infocus/nycm042712/s_n34_bpsi0651.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This reminded me of a &lt;a href='http://www.radiolab.org/2010/oct/08/belly-beast/'&gt;story I heard on RadioLab about &amp;#8216;Sandhogs,&amp;#8217;&lt;/a&gt; or the urban miners responsible for digging New York&amp;#8217;s tunnels under the Hudson and East rivers. They used shovels. To keep the tunnels from collapsing on the Sandhogs, engineers would pump the tunnels full of compressed air to sort of hold up the structure until it could be reinforced. But, getting the pressure just right was not always easily done. Sometimes a hole would form in the side of the tunnel and the air pressure would push everything, tools, materials, people, through that hole. There is one guy on the show who got sucked through one of these holes. Lucky for him, the pressure was so great that it pushed him through 60 feet of river bed, encapsulated him in an air bubble which pushed him to the top of the Hudson River, and then threw him hundreds of feet in the air. He landed back in the river, right alongside a police boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Safety standards for these colossal public works projects were generally pretty bad, I gather, but there is one iconic piece of infrastructure whose construction had an almost unblemished safety record: the Golden Gate Bridge. Joseph Strauss, the head engineer, was a fanatic for safety, ordering his workers to make use of such innovations as the hard hat and safety lines. He even had a giant safety net strung up underneath the bridge to catch anyone who was blown off by the frequent gusts. The net was almost as much of an engineering marvel as the bridge. &lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KLRCZAXfEa4'&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a little video about it.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href='http://mtprawvwdorlna1.nyc.gov/luna/servlet/allCollections'&gt;The entire NYC municipal photo archive can be found here.&lt;/a&gt; That&amp;#8217;s 870,000 pictures for your viewing pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>February 23, 1939 at the Moral Sciences Club</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2012/04/06/msc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2012/04/06/msc</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s only very occasionally that one comes across a real gem while doing archival research. Usually, archival material gives up its secrets slowly and piecemeal. But I found this entry the other day while going through the old minute books of the Moral Sciences Club, a philosophy society at Cambridge where presenters deliver a short paper, usually ten minutes, and then discuss with the other members for a few hours. From 1920 to 1950, a lot of exciting papers were given at the MSC by the likes of G. E. Moore, J. M. Keynes, H. L. A. Hart, John Wisdom, and Ludwig Wittgenstein.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the evening of February 23rd, 1939, Wittgenstein opened a general discussion with the question &amp;#8220;Why do philosophers ask what is the meaning of a word? Is it because they have forgotten?&amp;#8221; In the discussion that followed, the familiar claim that the meaning of a word can be found in its use came up. The &amp;#8220;meaning-as-use&amp;#8221; thesis is often considered one of the principle themes in Wittgenstein&amp;#8217;s philosophy, and is sometimes treated as if it had the status of &lt;em&gt;doctrine&lt;/em&gt; in his later philosophy. Wittgenstein&amp;#8217;s remarks on February 23rd make clear that no such interpretation of meaning-as-use can hold. A description of the use of a word itself always has a particular use, and thus ironically defeats any claims that trot out the phenomenon as a thesis. &amp;#8220;Philosophical investigations are tedious and difficult, and slip the memory. Slogans are easy, and stick in the memory. If the &lt;em&gt;use&lt;/em&gt; goes but the slogan remains, it is &lt;em&gt;ridiculous&lt;/em&gt;,&amp;#8221; Wittgenstein reportedly said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The full minutes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6th Meeting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feb 23rd, 1939&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#42;Doctor L. Wittgenstein&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sixth meeting of the term was held in Mr Smythies rooms in King’s. The Secretary was in the chair. There were two guests, Dr Ewing and Mr Braithwaite. Dr Wittgenstein spoke for a short time by way of opening the discussion. He put this question to those present: “Why do philosophers ask ‘what is the meaning of a word’, (a most common word)? ‘Have they forgotten the meaning of the term, etc.?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doctor Ewing thought the most important cases in which philosophers ask for the use of a word are cases in which they are doing something other than what they think they are doing, e.g., the case of physical objects. Mr Strachey suggested they were asking for definitions or at least trying to find out whether there can be a definition. Mr Braithwaite said he thought the philosopher was in a sense asking for an explicit description of the behavior of using the word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr Wittgenstein then asked how a definition acts as a coherent account of the use of a word. He said one might say that a definition draws together the usages of words. Augustine when he asks for the meaning of a word collects usages of the word. He reminds himself. If a definition is an account of the meaning isn’t it queer that people should forget it (Prince [referring to the previous week’s meeting, delivered by Mr D. Prince, titled “The use of a word”]), for surely a definition is a very simple thing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr Wittgenstein then asked what would be taken as the necessary qualifications for a definition to be an attempt at a coherent account of the use of a word. Must there not be a technique of working with symbols so that the definition seems to show the exact position of the word in question with respect to all these symbols. Suppose one defined number as Frege did, has one given a full account of the use of ‘number’ or ‘one’? No, there are actual uses of numbers which are not accounted for by it, e.g. counting people. Definition is one peculiar account of the use of the word. Only if you’ve mastered the technique of the language will you learn the word from the definition. In this sense a coherent account is not given by a definition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take the case of a physical object. Is it possible to define ‘cap’ by means of sense-data? Dr W thought it quite easy, but that it leads nowhere. Why do we want a coherent account at all? Philosophers only ask about certain words. Mr Braithwaite: They ask about words which are typical of a certain group, e.g. ‘table’, which is typical of a certain group. Dr W: Yes: but another thing is true, viz. if they do ask and they want a definition, they do not want the most natural definition, e.g. of ‘chair’ they don’t want the definition ‘something to sit on’. Why are they not satisfied with the normal definition of chair, or, to put the ma question in another way, why do they wish to ask for the definition of a physical object?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Earle suggested they wanted to define it in terms of philosophers’ words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr W asked whether one might say that the philosopher wanted to describe the relation between one type of word and another type of word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Partly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;St. Augustine found it so immensely difficult to find out what time was. What did he want to find out about time? Someone might say that St. Augustine was not puzzled about the usage of the word ‘time’, which is something pedestrian, but was puzzled about the essence of time which does not seem so pedestrian. Why was he puzzled?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Rush Rhees said puzzlement often occurred when there was a conflict of uses. Dr W: this is often called a contradiction. He cited a passage from Hertz’s Principles of Mechanics, in which the latter said that people ask about the essence of matter, etc., because a lot of defining criteria have been heaped on these notions, and these criteria are in conflict. This irritates our mind, and makes us ask ‘what is the essence of so and so?’ The answer is not given by giving further criteria, but by giving less [sic] criteria. When these contradictions are avoided, the question is not answered, but the mind no longer perplexed ceases to ask it. Dr W said he must confess that this passage seemed to him to sum up philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing is more characteristic of philosophy than to ask oneself the same question a thousand times. One case is that a person never stops doing this. Another case is that a person stops. What is given to him you to make it stop? Sometimes a new analogy, which replaces an old analogy. He had often pointed out that a child is perplexed when a word is seen to have two different meanings. If this is to cease to be puzzling it must be surrounded by other cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr W then went back to last week’s discussion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a vast number of cases it is possible to replace ‘the meaning of a word’ by ‘the use of a word.’ In what way is this useful. Mr Lewy: It may get rid of the idea that meaning is a picture attached to a word. Dr W: How does &lt;span&gt;sic&lt;/span&gt; the use and the picture hang together? Isn’t there an entirely parallel connexion, viz. between ostensive definition and use? Suppose I ask: What is a zebra? Does someone’s pointing to a picture of a zebra involve that he uses the word ‘zebra’ as we do? The connexion of image or picture and use is that as a matter of fact in an enormous number of cases to one particular image corresponds one particular use, and where it does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;, which is also an immense number of cases, there puzzlement arises. Why is it in a great number of cases useful to ask for the use and not the meaning? Because &lt;em&gt;meaning&lt;/em&gt; suggests one object, whereas use suggests a number of objects spread out in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In a great number of cases it is advisable to put ‘use of a word’ for ‘meaning of a word’”, is a slogan. Sometimes it is ridiculed: sometimes it is boosted. Both wrongly. If one does philosophy it is natural one should come to certain sorts of step which is advisable to take. Philosophical investigations are tedious and difficult, and slip the memory. Slogans are easy, and stick in the memory. If the &lt;em&gt;use&lt;/em&gt; goes but the slogan remains, it is &lt;em&gt;ridiculous&lt;/em&gt;. Dr W said that although he had often used the words of the slogan, he had never had need to call it anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a colossally important fact that all objects around us have &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; name. What is this a principle of?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theodore Redpath (Honorable Secretary)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;em&gt;Cambridge University Archives&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here is some entertaining marginalia found in a library copy of the &lt;em&gt;Tractatus Logico-Philosophicus&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Cheeky boy' src='/img/posts/tlp.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AdSense</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2012/03/26/adsense/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2012/03/26/adsense</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Look under &amp;#8220;More about&amp;#8230;&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='What Google knows' src='/img/posts/sidebar.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href='https://plus.google.com/116169008388909822914'&gt;MDM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Istanbul</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2012/03/24/istanbul/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2012/03/24/istanbul</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, I escaped the inter-term somnolence of Cambridge for the brilliance of Istanbul. Tickets purchased only days before, I handed in my paper for the term and rode the train south into London through the rain with a coursemate. We would arrive in Istanbul at 4 am and meet another coursemate who had jumped Cambridge the day before and &lt;a href='http://adelicatething.tumblr.com/'&gt;a good friend of mine traveling and writing in the region.&lt;/a&gt; Istanbul is a striking city, even at 4 am and taken in without sleep and wearied by in-flight drinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Sultanahmet at sunset' src='/img/posts/istanbul3.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one, it is enormous. The city is growing tremendously. New highways and metro lines connect the bunches of high-rise apartment blocks stretching west of the old city. The metropolitan area extends in all directions and technically encompasses (and administers) areas as far from historic walls of the city as the Prince&amp;#8217;s Islands, 20 km southwest of the central neighborhood of Sultanahmet in the Sea of Marmara. We stayed in a wonderful hostel in Beyoğlu, a populous neighborhood across the Golden Horn from the tourist-laden Sultanahmet. The main pedestrian drag, Istiklal, was packed with people every night. On our second night, the local football team, Galatasaray, beat Fenerbahçe, a team from across town. Istiklal was quickly filled with fans who were mostly content to parade down the street. Things got tense briefly when a Galatasaray supporter noticed an unfortunate kid wearing a Fenerbahçe jersey and rushed at him. To the credit of Galatasaray fans, several Galatasaray supporters intervened and whisked the Fenerbahçe kid (probably 12 years old) into the back of a nearby shop where the crowd couldn&amp;#8217;t get at him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Galatasaray wins' src='/img/posts/istanbul9.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our merry band of four travelers initially did a good job seeing the sights. We spent a sunny afternoon in Sultanahmet, visiting the Blue Mosque, Haghia Sofia, and Topkapi Palace (though we &lt;em&gt;twice&lt;/em&gt; missed the museum&amp;#8217;s opening hours). A was excited to have the chance to pray in some of Istanbul&amp;#8217;s many, breath-taking mosques. We non-faithful were happy to sit outside and enjoy the sights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Phototouristas' src='/img/posts/istanbul10.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Arjun at the Blue Mosque' src='/img/posts/istanbul4.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='The faithful in the Blue Mosque' src='/img/posts/istanbul11.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Haghia Sofia (Ayasofia) was really quite strange. It&amp;#8217;s ancient, and feels like it. The building has been added to over the years, accumulating new wings, minarets, and flying buttresses as empires changed and the building grew beyond its original structural capacities. While it is aesthetically coherent, in person you can see the different ages of the various parts of the building, giving its permanence an uncanny countenance. Inside the roof is decorated with Byzantine icons. I took especial note of the four cherubs decorating the pendentives. Cherubs really are quite ghastly creatures: six-winged, four-faced creatures &lt;a href='http://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Ezekiel%201:13&amp;amp;version=NIV'&gt;&amp;#8220;resembling living fire.&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; The Ottomans covered the faces of the four Cherubs in the Haghia Sofia, but one has been restored. Tremble:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Ecce Cherubim' src='/img/posts/istanbul1.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Inside the Haghia Sofia' src='/img/posts/istanbul2.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also happened to pay a visit to the massive Turkish Military Museum on the day the Turkish state commemorates the battle of the Dardanelles. Thus, we scored free admission and had the added cultural benefit of witnessing the considerable number of museum visitors, giving some sense of the meaning of the holiday to contemporary Turks. The museum exhibits consisted mostly of Ottoman-era weaponry and armor. There is also a good amount of space dedicated to the founding of the republic, as one would expect, and a few rooms about Atatürk. There is something like a state-sponsored cult of personality around Atatürk, and I confess I gathered no sense of how this narrative sits with contemporary Turks of any political leaning. I did hear mention of Kemalists, though I do not know how big of a section of the Turkish political spectrum this is, or what their relationship is to the current nationalist government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Exhibit of Atatürks classroom at military academy' src='/img/posts/istanbul8.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our fearless touring and the just-ended Cambridge term soon caught up with us, however, and we spent a lot of time in Istanbul relaxing in the sun. Many glasses of tea were drunk, several books were read, panoramas were taken in, and lots of games of cards were played. It was a wonderful respite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='The Bosphorus' src='/img/posts/istanbul6.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You all should go if you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Seraglio Point from the Bosphorus' src='/img/posts/istanbul5.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snow!</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2012/02/05/snow-in-cambridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2012 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2012/02/05/snow-in-cambridge</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night, Cambridge got its once-annual snowstorm. This morning the town was covered in a half-foot of snow and everyone was out and about with cameras to capture the scene. It was very pretty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Parkers Piece is a little windblown' src='/img/posts/camsnow3.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parker&amp;#8217;s Piece in Cambridge is like the Midway Plaisance in Hyde Park. A wide open, windblown green space that some poor souls have to trek across daily. There was a joke that Satan was at the end of the Midway, &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dante&amp;apos;s_Satan'&gt;blasting it with the cold wind from his wings&lt;/a&gt;. Parker&amp;#8217;s Piece kind of feels like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Cold ass dude' src='http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/4/44/Gustave_Dore_Inferno34.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As counterpoint, and also because it is obligatory when photographing Cambridge, here is a picture of King&amp;#8217;s Chapel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Das Haus Gottes' src='/img/posts/camsnow4.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, we snuck into St. John&amp;#8217;s back quad. It was a very pretty scene, despite the snow phallus some mature undergrads had constructed. Perhaps the ghosts that supposedly haunt this bridge will teach those kids a lesson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Ye olde Bridge of Sighs' src='/img/posts/camsnow2.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During World War II, the story goes, Hitler chose not to bomb Cambridge because he so adored this building. I&amp;#8217;m almost certain the tale is totally spurious, but there &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a pretty fierce looking eagle above the building&amp;#8217;s main portal. Fishy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='The building that saved Cambridge' src='/img/posts/camsnow1.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here we all are, a little dehydrated and tired, but happy at the end of our trek.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Hughesians' src='/img/posts/camsnow5.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Novels in 140 Characters</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2012/01/31/novels-in-140-characters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2012/01/31/novels-in-140-characters</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Twitters newest postmodern voice' src='/img/posts/cfd1.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advancing the Twitter-as-literature genre by leaps and bounds, the Chicago Fire Department&amp;#8217;s new Twitter account, &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/#!/CFDMedia'&gt;@CFDMedia&lt;/a&gt;, has burst onto the scene with a flurry of postmodern tweets that are somewhere between the clipped reports of a police scanner and baffling personal appeals. I think it captures the (non) audience of Twitter perfectly. They also appear to be sent from a BlackBerry. City of Chicago standard issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Its just kind of weird' src='/img/posts/cfd2.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tweets remind me of Felix Feneon&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href='http://www.nybooks.com/books/imprints/classics/novels-in-three-lines/'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Novels in Three Lines&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a collection of the several line long news entries Feneon wrote anonymously for &lt;em&gt;Le Matin&lt;/em&gt; at the turn of the 20th century. Feneon had a real talent for suggestion, irony, and pathos. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&quot;A  complaint was sworn by the Persian physician Djai Khan against a compatriot who had stolen from him a tiara.&quot;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;No more briar pipes. Their makers, in Saint-Claude, have stopped work until they are paid better.&quot;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;&quot;If my candidate loses, I will kill myself,&quot; M. Bellavoine, of Fresquienne, Seine-Inferieure, had declared. He killed himself.&quot;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not saying @CFDMedia is like Feneon, and I think the facile Twitter/Novels in Three Lines similarity has been pointed out before, but its worth following this account.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Gaffney, 1996-2011</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2011/11/10/rip-happy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2011 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2011/11/10/rip-happy</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Happy' src='/img/posts/hap1.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Happy' src='/img/posts/hap2.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Happy' src='/img/posts/hap4.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Happy' src='/img/posts/hap3.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Happy' src='/img/posts/hap6.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This is Chicagoland</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2011/11/05/this-is-chicagoland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2011/11/05/this-is-chicagoland</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Saw this photo today, titled &amp;#8220;Autumn in Chicagoland&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Autumn in Chicagoland' src='http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6092/6226873344_926c3bfbab_b.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/dwquinn79/'&gt;David Quinn&lt;/a&gt; took the photo &amp;#8220;in the Palatine or Rolling Meadows suburbs&amp;#8221; of Chicago. It reminded me immediately of Jason Lazarus&amp;#8217;s photograph &amp;#8220;Standing at the Grave of Emmett Till, Day of Exhumation, June 1st, 2005 (Alsip, IL)&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Standing at the Grave of Emmett Till, Day of Exhumation, June 1st, 2005 (Alsip, IL)' src='http://arttattler.com/Images/NorthAmerica/Illinois/Chicago/Renaissance%20Society/Black%20Ain&amp;apos;t/EmmetTill.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think both photographs capture something uncanny about Chicago&amp;#8217;s suburban spaces. Both show a scar through manicured, humanless landscapes that look remarkably like backyards. One is a golf course, the other is a cemetery.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Impressions of Cambridge</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2011/10/12/first-impressions-of-cambridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2011/10/12/first-impressions-of-cambridge</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is long overdue and too brief. I arrived in Cambridge, England just about two weeks ago to begin an MPhil in Political Thought and Intellectual History at, of course, the University of Cambridge. The program(me) has both taught and research components, though the focus is largely on the student&amp;#8217;s research. This will be a substantial change from what I got used to as an undergraduate, but it&amp;#8217;s a welcome one. I would write &lt;em&gt;ad nauseum&lt;/em&gt; about what I&amp;#8217;ll be researching &lt;em&gt;ad nauseum&lt;/em&gt;, but the program has an evaluation scheme whereby papers are read without knowing the authors, and any tips as to who will be writing what are unwelcome. So, in the interest of academic integrity, and most likely in the reader&amp;#8217;s general interest as well, I&amp;#8217;ll keep my work to myself for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Welcome to sunny Cambridge' src='/img/posts/cam_weather.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that needs to be said is that the weather has been remarkably nice since I&amp;#8217;ve arrived. This really is a big deal since most days out of the year the United Kingdom is a dim, wet place. I&amp;#8217;m housed in one of the livelier and more diverse parts of Cambridge: Mill Road. There are lots of &amp;#8220;ethnic&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;international&amp;#8221; restaurants and groceries on Mill Road, including the local Al Amin grocery, whose owner, Abdul Arain is running for chancellor of Cambridge against Lord Sainsbury, the heir-apparent and owner of one of the UK&amp;#8217;s largest supermarket chains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also of note in my neighborhood is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.cb1.com/'&gt;CB 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8211; the world&amp;#8217;s first internet cafe! Some have joked that it also may be the last. Regardless, it&amp;#8217;s one of the nicer places to read in Cambridge. And since the libraries close here around 7 pm, having a good cafe nearby that&amp;#8217;s open late is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll have to make some more comments later about the college system, its perpetuation of structural inequalities, and the dispersion of administration that sets Cambridge pretty far apart from American universities as institutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dillon, Texas</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2011/09/07/dillon%2C-texas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2011/09/07/dillon,-texas</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I started rewatching &lt;em&gt;Friday Night Lights&lt;/em&gt; recently and have been taking notice how the show&amp;#8217;s story changes over the course of the five seasons. I haven&amp;#8217;t given energy to plot or character changes, but I have noticed how the show changes its portrayal of the very site and origin of the Panthers/Lions tale: Dillon, Texas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the central themes of the show is how hard-working, good-hearted women and men overcome the very basic and ingrained adversity of their circumstances. Matt Saracen rises to the challenge and leads his team to a state championship, despite having no immediate leaders in his family life. Tim Riggins time and time again pushes aside his inner demons and does the right thing. And most extremely, Vince Howard transforms himself from Another Young Black Criminal to the virtuous leader of his family and team. He becomes the man he always was on the inside. This is the story of &lt;em&gt;Friday Night Lights&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#8211;that individuals can overcome their class and race positions, their poor upbringing, in short, whatever shit they were born into&amp;#8211;and I think it is a good one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this is what makes the subtle change in the show&amp;#8217;s portrayal of Dillon interesting. As the site of most of the characters&amp;#8217; adversities&amp;#8211;and it&amp;#8217;s a refrain among the characters that if they could just get out of Dillon, they would leave all these difficulties behind&amp;#8211;it&amp;#8217;s interesting to see the show shift from portraying the Dillon landscape as depressed, isolating, and ex-urban to bright, nurturing, and more rural.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best measure of the show&amp;#8217;s portrayal of place are the scene setting shots of Dillon from a moving vehicle. They work almost like intertitles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are some from Season One:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Dillon, Texas, Season One' src='/img/posts/fnl-s1-5.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Dillon, Texas, Season One' src='/img/posts/fnl-s1-4.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Dillon, Texas, Season One' src='/img/posts/fnl-s1-3.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Dillon, Texas, Season One' src='/img/posts/fnl-s1-2.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Dillon, Texas, Season One' src='/img/posts/fnl-s1-6.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Dillon, Texas, Season One' src='/img/posts/fnl-s1-1.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And here are some from Season Five:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Dillon, Texas, Season Five' src='/img/posts/fnl-s5-4.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Dillon, Texas, Season Five' src='/img/posts/fnl-s5-5.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Dillon, Texas, Season Five' src='/img/posts/fnl-s5-1.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Dillon, Texas, Season Five' src='/img/posts/fnl-s5-2.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Dillon, Texas, Season Five' src='/img/posts/fnl-s5-6.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this last shot, the dialogue is actually:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Becky&lt;/em&gt;: It&amp;#8217;s so pretty out here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Luke&lt;/em&gt;: I used to hate it here. My whole life I figured football was gonna take me outta here. I couldn&amp;#8217;t imagine staying around here&amp;#8230;but&amp;#8230;I guess I better try to imagine it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Becky&lt;/em&gt;: I have an amazing imagination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Luke&lt;/em&gt;: You ever think you could imagine living on a farm?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Becky&lt;/em&gt;: Sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luke and Becky are talking about staying in Dillon. Furthermore, one of the last shots of the final season is of Tim and Billy Riggins building a house in Dillon at sunset. It&amp;#8217;s almost as if we&amp;#8217;ve witnessed the transformation of the town from a place of adversity and disadvantage to a place of redemption and hope. It certainly has transformed from a place of escape to one of return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is interesting for two reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) This narrative affirms the logic of nostalgia which is so critically examined in the first season, as well as in the movie and book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) This dulls the show&amp;#8217;s social comment that the adversity these characters face may be &lt;em&gt;caused by&lt;/em&gt; the place, i.e. the social, political, and economic circumstances that these characters are in. In this very small way, by dissociating the town of Dillon, Texas from the institutional difficulties the characters face, the show seems to be removing their adversity from larger societal trends, such as racism, classism, or discrepancies in education.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neo-Locals</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2011/08/14/neo-locals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2011/08/14/neo-locals</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The other day I took a ride through a relatively new sub-division next to the neighborhood where my parents live. This new sub-division is called Nassau Grove and it&amp;#8217;s built and designed by the national housing chain K. Hovnanian, from New Jersey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a really strange place. To begin with, the name doesn&amp;#8217;t make too much sense. There is a tiny municipality called Nassau (an old train depot, I think) near present-day Nassau Grove, but there&amp;#8217;s no grove as far as I know. The sub-division has followed the usual pattern of Sussex county development: farms to modular homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is &amp;#8220;Nassau Grove&amp;#8221; ten years ago:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Sussex County, circa 1992' src='/img/posts/de-hay.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is Nassau Grove today:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Pleasantville' src='/img/posts/pleasantville.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My dad refers to Nassau Grove as &amp;#8220;Pleasantville,&amp;#8221; and it is actually quite striking how unreal the place is. For one, all the streets are named after French wines: Grenache Ct, Chablis Ln, Nouveau Ave, uzw. But more importantly, it&amp;#8217;s not clear who actually lives in Nassau Grove. K. Hovnanian built most of the houses in one go, assuming they would sell without any trouble. Then the recession hit, and modular homes that were selling in the &amp;#8220;upper 500s&amp;#8221; (as advertised) are now in the &amp;#8220;lower 200s.&amp;#8221; Most of the homes are unoccupied, and I find myself doing a double take whenever I see someone sitting on a porch or walking down Anjou Ct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from taking the place of a local farm and adding congestion to Sussex County&amp;#8217;s poorly planned road network, places like Nassau Grove are mostly harmless (though there are plenty of cases of local landowners getting swindled by developers and selling their land for about 10% of its actual value). However, I think that the rapid development of Sussex County has wrought some more subtle cultural damage that is harder to notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sense of community in Lewes and Rehoboth is now highly ambiguous. Growing up it felt quite coherent, if prejudiced and exclusive. Take as an example a single beach called the naval jetty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='The naval jetty' src='/img/posts/naval-jetty.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing up, the naval jetty was a part of the beach few people went to. It was a bit out of the way compared to the main Cape Henlopen and Rehoboth beaches of the area, and it has lots of obstructions in the water and sand that make it a bit more dangerous. But, it had a nice break, so lots of people went there to surf. You could count on meeting someone you knew there, and more than once as a kid my parents just dropped me off at the beach, assuming that I&amp;#8217;d be able to get a ride home with someone&amp;#8217;s folks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, if you go down to the naval jetty you&amp;#8217;ll see the beach packed with tourists, and some accompanying graffiti like &amp;#8220;NO KOOKS&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;GO BACK TO PA.&amp;#8221; I appreciate the defensive sentiment, but I think it&amp;#8217;s coming from a confused place. I was down at the naval jetty the other day, waiting in the line-up with about a million other people, when I was told to &amp;#8220;get off the locals&amp;#8217; beach&amp;#8221; by a middle-aged man who I happened to know was a dentist from upstate with a beach house in Lewes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an actual local, I was initially pretty upset with this jerk, but soon grew confused over what sort of circumstances would give someone permission to behave like this. I realized that the local population, and any claim to local-legitimacy, was so radically in flux because of the massive population growth and radical socio-economic change in the area, that it&amp;#8217;s basically a &lt;em&gt;total&lt;/em&gt; free-for-all in the arena of who-is-who in the rapidly changing rural-to-exurban Sussex County.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the category of local is so radically in question, and so many are making various types of claims to it, I think the only appropriate category in action now is the neo-local.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s weird.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Wheels</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2011/08/13/new-wheels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2011/08/13/new-wheels</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After years of making due with generously donated but poorly fitting bikes, I finally have a steed to call my own: a Salsa Casseroll. I was looking for an affordable road bike that could do long rides comfortably and would stand up in all seasons and conditions. I was initially drawn to the &lt;a href='http://surlybikes.com/bikes/pacer_complete/'&gt;Surly Pacer&lt;/a&gt;, which I&amp;#8217;ve read is an outstanding bike (and comes in sick racing green!), but I quickly became enamored with the new &lt;a href='http://salsacycles.com/bikes/casseroll/'&gt;Salsa Casseroll&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='My new bike down at North Shores' src='/img/posts/casseroll-at-north-shores.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Casseroll is &amp;#8220;a relaxed road bike,&amp;#8221; which means a solid steel frame with more traditional road geometry, but a slightly extended head tube, 32 cm tires, and a sweet included front rack for out-of-the-box randonneuring. I decided on the Casseroll over a more traditional road bike because I&amp;#8217;m hoping to do some longer rides and maybe one day a few centuries. I know I felt joint and back fatigue acutely during longer rides in the past on my more aggressively configured bikes, and was looking for a more sustainable way of riding farther.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far I am extremely pleased with the Casseroll. I won&amp;#8217;t be winning any races with these tires and my upright posture, but I&amp;#8217;ve been able to cruise at a healthy clip for a while without feeling stress anywhere but my thigh muscles. You can still sprint efficiently, and the generous drops let you get quite low and wide for fast descents and powering through corners. It&amp;#8217;s a really versatile bike. I&amp;#8217;ve taken it on gravel paths without a second thought. My real &amp;#8221;I&amp;#8217;m happy I own a Casseroll&amp;#8221; moment came the other night when I was just pedaling around the neighborhood and went off exploring in an unfinished sub-development with a mix of paved and unpaved roads. I didn&amp;#8217;t have to worry about the bike at all; I was carefree. I&amp;#8217;m sure anyone with a solid hybrid or mountain bike will have this same experience, but on the Casseroll, I could quickly ride the two paved miles home without breaking a sweat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving this blog</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2011/08/02/moving-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2011/08/02/moving-this-blog</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To add to the large collection of posts praising the move from WordPress to &lt;a href='https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki'&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;: I moved my blog from WordPress to Jekyll today. I&amp;#8217;m a very slow worker, a ruminator (as my mom tells me), prone to idiotic syntax errors, and it still only took me a few hours to install Jekyll, build some templates, and migrate my old stuff. Now, this blog is flying free courtesy of GitHub and Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did I switch platforms? Mostly because I wanted to learn something new. GitHub is an incredibly useful tool, and I wanted to familiarize myself with the workflow of versioning, testing locally, and deploying that more applications-oriented development requires. Using Jekyll is actually a great introduction to git and GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The student&amp;#8217;s perspective aside, what is the advantage of Jekyll over WordPress? Well, for my needs I prefer Jekyll&amp;#8217;s smaller size, more intuitive templating process, and simple layout. I have to prepare myself each time I start a new WordPress project and begin contorting the default theme to my needs. Perhaps my approach is all wrong, but I end up wading through and cutting loose most of what WordPress prepackages when I make the relatively simple sites I do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll doesn&amp;#8217;t break down the main page into six (or seven?) component PHP files or anything like that. You have your default page template, which lets you put, in plain old HTML, whatever you&amp;#8217;d like around your content, and you have your post template, which lets you add HTML or dynamic elements you&amp;#8217;d like into your individual posts. Jekyll is basically a text to HTML engine, so the idea is to configure how you&amp;#8217;d like your posts to be HTMLed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Herein lies the benefit and limit of Jekyll when compared to WordPress. WordPress is extremely extendable, can handle multiple different types of content, and has a very nice off-the-shelf backend. It is an extremely capable CMS, but may be a bit too hefty for a simple little blog. It&amp;#8217;s way bigger than Jekyll, which makes it more versatile, but a little less useable for simple applications like this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still think WordPress is great. It&amp;#8217;s amazing software. And free! And everyone uses it, so there are tons of neat WP things out there, as well as lots of excellent documentation and support. But, for those of you just blogging, and who are not into Tumblr, Posterous, Blogspot, etc., give Jekyll a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get Jekyll going for free on GitHub, you&amp;#8217;ll need to know HTML, CSS, and a little bit of &lt;a href='http://git-scm.com/'&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;. They&amp;#8217;re all worth learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='CMS for Jekyll' src='/img/posts/finder.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is Jekyll&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;CMS&amp;#8221;! It&amp;#8217;s great! It&amp;#8217;s a folder on your computer!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bildungsbürgertum</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2011/05/27/bildungsburgertum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2011/05/27/bildungsburgertum</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not sure how I feel about how people use the word &amp;#8220;hipster&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; it seems to be a pretty essentialist pejorative that has a lot of dangers lurking behind it &amp;#8211; but I think often when people use the word they are actually referring to a complex and deep historical phenomenon of the European middle-class. Maybe we&amp;#8217;re better off using the word &lt;em&gt;Bildungsbürgertum&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;The concrete sociopolitical embodiment of the idea of a self-regulating aesthetic society was the so called &lt;em&gt;Bildungsbürgertum&lt;/em&gt;, the &quot;educated middle classes,&quot; who, although excluded from the exercise of serious forms of independent political power virtually everywhere, used their purported possession of a cultivated faculty of aesthetic judgment, their taste, to legitimize the retention of a certain socially privileged postion. Membership in this group, the &lt;em&gt;Bildungsbürgertum&lt;/em&gt;, was not supposed to be guaranteed by noble birth, inherited wealth, or economic success, but was to be granted by the free recognition of one's (good) taste on the part of others who were themselves in a postion to judge. The &lt;em&gt;Bildungsbürgertum&lt;/em&gt; was a self-coopting group whose collective good taste was a tacit warrant (almost) of moral superiority. (Raymond Geuss, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.scribd.com/doc/26127994/Geuss-Kultur-Bildung-Geist'&gt;Kultur, Bildung, Geist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might be a good idea to take note of the &lt;em&gt;Bildungsbürgertum&lt;/em&gt; and the history of the aesthetics of the middle-class since we have the 19th century European middle-class to thank for a number of things: from museums to kitsch. Just sayin&amp;#8217;, if we&amp;#8217;re going to pass judgement on something, let&amp;#8217;s make sure we know what exactly it is first.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Note on RVM on Macs</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2011/05/19/a-note-on-rvm-on-macs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2011/05/19/a-note-on-rvm-on-macs</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m just diving into Rails (great tutorials on Ruby &lt;a href='http://pine.fm/LearnToProgram/'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, on Rails &lt;a href='http://www.railsforzombies.org'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='http://ruby.railstutorial.org/ruby-on-rails-tutorial-book'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) and ran into a very small bump in the road this morning that some Mac users might have. It&amp;#8217;s an easy problem to troubleshoot, but I thought I would put my Google findings in one place for anyone who is also running into this issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently the version of Ruby that ships with Snow Leopard has some trouble compiling and also is a bit older so can&amp;#8217;t support Rails 3. You can deal with this by installing multiple versions of Ruby on your machine using &lt;a href='https://rvm.beginrescueend.com'&gt;Ruby Version Manager&lt;/a&gt; (RVM). There are some very straightforward installation instructions on RVM&amp;#8217;s site, but for Mac users there are a few extra steps you&amp;#8217;ll need to do to tell your machine where RVM is, and to tell it how to find RVM, and consequently which version of Ruby you choose, each time you open Terminal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First you&amp;#8217;ll want to install RVM from Terminal by running&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
	bash &amp;lt; &amp;lt;( curl http://rvm.beginrescueend.com/releases/rvm-install-head)
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;ll then have to tell Terminal where to find RVM by running&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
	[[ -s &quot;$HOME/.rvm/scripts/rvm&quot; ]] &amp;amp;&amp;amp; . &quot;$HOME/.rvm/scripts/rvm&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will tell Terminal where to find RVM for this session you&amp;#8217;re in, but to tell Terminal to find RVM each time you open a shell, you&amp;#8217;ll have to add it permanently to your .bash_profile. If, like me, you don&amp;#8217;t have a .bash_profile (Terminal doesn&amp;#8217;t create one for you by default), no worries. Just create one by typing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
	touch .bash_profile
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to create the file and edit it using any old text editor or run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
	open -e .bash_profile
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to open it in Text Editor. Add our line&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
	[[ -s &quot;$HOME/.rvm/scripts/rvm&quot; ]] &amp;amp;&amp;amp; . &quot;$HOME/.rvm/scripts/rvm&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to .bash_profile, save it, and now Terminal will know where to find RVM each time you start a new session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, now you&amp;#8217;ve downloaded some exciting new versions of Ruby using RVM. Want to use one by default? RVM can do that for you, too. Just run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
	rvm use 1.9.2 --default
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and now you&amp;#8217;re humming along on Ruby 1.9.2 (if you have installed it, of course). Check it by running&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
	ruby -v
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of this I learned from &lt;a href='http://seanbehan.com/mac-os-x/installing-and-using-rvm-on-mac-os-x-creating-gemsets-and-reverting-to-original-environment/'&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;. It has some more helpful info, so check it out if you have any questions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Well Reasoned Argument</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2011/04/27/a-well-reasoned-argument/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2011/04/27/a-well-reasoned-argument</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style='font-style:italic;'&gt;
What follows is an email I received from a dear roommate continuing a conversation the apartment had been having earlier in the day about whether or not to throw a party (we were in college at the time). I found it buried in my inbox today. It remains to this day one of the finer examples of argumentation I have seen, and in its spirit, I would even compare it &lt;a href='https://www.msu.edu/~tyrrell/LYSIAS.htm' target='_blank'&gt;Lysias's funeral oration&lt;/a&gt;. Enjoy:
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;div style='color: #404040;'&gt;
	from	REDACTED@uchicago.edu&lt;br /&gt;
	to	REDACTED@uchicago.edu,&lt;br /&gt;
		REDACTED@gmail.com,&lt;br /&gt;
		REDACTED@uchicago.edu&lt;br /&gt;
	date	Mon, Nov 5, 2007 at 1:38 AM&lt;br /&gt;
	subject	Partay&lt;br /&gt;
	mailed-by	uchicago.edu&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;
After careful consideration, I think it is very important that&lt;br /&gt;
we throw a raging kegger.  These being the final days of our&lt;br /&gt;
formative years, the opportunities to get wildly drunk and act&lt;br /&gt;
with utter disregard and abandon will be fewer and fewer&lt;br /&gt;
until, god forbid, we become respectable people.  Further, it&lt;br /&gt;
is commonly known that the typical Uchicago party is wanting&lt;br /&gt;
in spirit and verve; by throwing a raging kegger we can buck&lt;br /&gt;
this pervasive and unhealthy trend.  I have been to many&lt;br /&gt;
parties where people were simply too sober and, though I&lt;br /&gt;
enjoyed the party, I came away thinking that it would be&lt;br /&gt;
really great if everyone were just a bit crazier and yes,&lt;br /&gt;
sloppier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I think a keg is important for facilitating the atmosphere&lt;br /&gt;
necessary for a raging kegger.  Kegs are also cheaper than a&lt;br /&gt;
comparable quantity of cans or bottles.  Most people prefer&lt;br /&gt;
draft beer to other sorts of beer.  While its true, kegs are a&lt;br /&gt;
hassle, the increased effort will be worth the cost&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Beer pong is also an important aspect of a raging kegger.  I&lt;br /&gt;
know that it is not in vogue on our campus.  In fact, a great&lt;br /&gt;
stigma seems to be attached towards the activity.  However,&lt;br /&gt;
beer pong is a fun activity that encourages a friendly spirit&lt;br /&gt;
of competition.  Yes, beer pong is messy, but parties are&lt;br /&gt;
generally messy (even if they're not raging keggers).  Our&lt;br /&gt;
floors need a good mopping anyway; we should resolve to mop&lt;br /&gt;
Sunday afternoon regardless of how messy the party gets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I understand that a raging kegger may seem garrulous and&lt;br /&gt;
fratty.  However, considering our well known and well defined&lt;br /&gt;
personalities combined with our equally well established&lt;br /&gt;
credentials as non-frat people, I suspect most recipients of&lt;br /&gt;
the e-mail invitation will understand our conscientious use of&lt;br /&gt;
the phrase and find it ironic and entirely consistent with our&lt;br /&gt;
personalities and m.o.  Since we will, in fact, be throwing a&lt;br /&gt;
raging kegger, we get to have our cake and eat it too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Respectfully disagreeing with ---, I think there is a&lt;br /&gt;
difference between BYOB and &quot;contributions welcome.&quot;  In my&lt;br /&gt;
experience, BYOB is code for &quot;there won't be much alcohol&quot;&lt;br /&gt;
while &quot;contributions welcome&quot; has a meaning more akin to: &quot;be&lt;br /&gt;
a good person; help us defray the cost of the party.&quot;  In&lt;br /&gt;
general, there have been far too many potluck style&lt;br /&gt;
house-parties lately and not enough instances of old fashioned&lt;br /&gt;
hospitality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I welcome discussion on any of the matters above.  I think its [sic]&lt;br /&gt;
important we're all together and committed to the vision of&lt;br /&gt;
our party, regardless of what that vision ends up being. It&lt;br /&gt;
is important we have a clear idea of said vision in the&lt;br /&gt;
immediate future so we can get an invite out.  As far as&lt;br /&gt;
discussion goes, I think its important that we don't regard a&lt;br /&gt;
tame, traditional apartment party as the status quo by which&lt;br /&gt;
alternatives (namely the raging kegger) must prove themselves&lt;br /&gt;
superior, but rather hold to each option equally rigorous&lt;br /&gt;
standards of justification.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imitation of Life</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2011/03/13/imitation-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2011/03/13/imitation-of-life</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The title sequence of Douglas Sirk&amp;#8217;s &lt;em&gt;Imitation of Life&lt;/em&gt; is pretty stunning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;object height='349' width='560'&gt;&lt;param name='movie' value='http://www.youtube.com/v/iGZ7NJ2rgyM?fs=1&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;rel=0' /&gt;&lt;param name='allowFullScreen' value='true' /&gt;&lt;param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /&gt;&lt;embed allowfullscreen='true' allowscriptaccess='always' height='349' src='http://www.youtube.com/v/iGZ7NJ2rgyM?fs=1&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;rel=0' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' width='560' /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.haroldsfonts.com/imitation.html'&gt;And in case you wanted that font.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a Caper</title>
      <link>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2011/03/08/what-a-caper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2011 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>conorsg@gmail.com (Conor Gaffney)</author>
      <guid>http://www.conorgaffney.com/2011/03/08/what-a-caper</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As Scott &lt;a href='http://scottvdp.com/2011/03/08/introducing-chicago2011-org/'&gt;has already put it&lt;/a&gt;, after a whirlwind six days, an excellent team of most righteous dudes - Harper Reed, Dylan Richard, Scott VanDenPlas, Aaron Salmon, and Scott Robbin - put together a great site for Rahm&amp;#8217;s transition team. In record time, they conceptualized, wrote, tested, and finally overcame a most inopportune App Engine fail to launch &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.chicago2011.org'&gt;Chicago2011.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to a &lt;a href='http://www.chicago2011.org/blog/statement-from-david-hoffman-on-this-site'&gt;warm reception&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a great experience and I&amp;#8217;m grateful for the opportunity to have worked with such excellent people. And, importantly, Chicago2011.org is doing quite well. We&amp;#8217;ve had a good number of visitors so far, and users have submitted &lt;a href='http://www.chicago2011.org/issues/fiscally-sound-government/'&gt;some pretty excellent&lt;/a&gt; proposals on the Interact tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll be excited to keep working on this project and seeing how far it can go.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    

  </channel> 
</rss>